Jonathan Gumero

(832) 775-3445 • jongumero@gmail.com • jongumero.github.io

Software Engineer

I am a dedicated Software & Design Engineer with 2 years of experience in the design, coding, analysis, and testing of complex systems. I'm excited to bring my skills in developing efficient, reliable embedded software and optimizing system functionality and performance. Experience collaborating with teams to create reliable software and align developments with both business and system requirements. Proven ability to deliver under tight timelines, as evidenced by the implementation of 6 detailed installation and testing procedures at Duke Energy, which reduced equipment downtime by 15%, saving 30+ hours of downtime.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Duke Energy • Raleigh, NC • Full-time

Jul 2022 - Present

Electrical Design Engineer

- Reduced design errors by 30% by managing and revising over 100 technical drawings in a \$20M Large Power Transformer project, saving total project workload by 100+ hours.
- Aided in reducing equipment downtime by 15% by introducing 6 highly detailed installation and testing procedures, resulting in an annual company savings of \$240,000.
- Decreased breaker-related safety incidents by leading the full design change of 55 obsolete circuit breakers, resulting in \$18,000 and 200 work hours saved each year.
- Increased plant compliance by 10% by evaluating and revising over 20 calculation documents, ensuring the plant's strict adherence to industry standards.

U.S. Air Force • Oklahoma City, OK • Internship

May 2021 - Aug 2021

Software Engineer

- Created 50+ unit tests to reduce system troubleshooting errors by 7% saving the team over 300 hours of yearly testing time.
- Improved code robustness by 8% compared to previous versions by debugging over 5000 lines of code, resulting in a 10% improved system performance.
- Developed a new scripting program that simulates military flight missions, leading to an increase in information and mission planning efficiency by 13%.
- Created and designed a full-scale mobile application game using C# and Unity to showcase front-end and UI design skills at end of internship.

EDUCATION

B.S. in Electrical Engineering

Texas A&M University • College Station, TX • GPA: 3.75

Aug 2018 - May 2022

SKILLS

Skills: Swift, UlKit, XCode, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, C#, C++, Python, Debugging, Web Design, Mobile Development, Agile